Good evening ladies and gentlemen and a
very warm welcome to ICIC Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited Q3 and
9mon FI2025 earnings conference call
from the senior management we have with
us today Mr. Sanjiv Mantri MD and CEO of
the company Mr. Gopal Balachandran CFO
Mr. Girish Nyak chief technology and
health underwriting and claims Mr. Sep
Goradia, chief corporate solutions
group. Mr. Anam Singhi, chief retail and
government business and Mr. Go Aurora,
chief underwriting and claims for
property and casualty.
Please note that any statements,
comments are made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involved risk and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being expressed.
As a reminder, all participant lines
will be in the listenonly mode and there
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes.
Should you need assistance during the
conference call, please signal an
operator by pressing star then zero on
your touchstone phone. I now hand the
conference over to Mr. Sanji Mantri, MD
and CEO, ICICA Lombard General Insurance
Limited. Thank you and over to you sir.
Thank you so much.
Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call of ICL O Lombard for quarter 3 and
9 months financial year 2025.
At the outset, let me wish you all a
very happy new year.
As I complete first year in my current
role, I'm excited to share developments
we have made together since we connected
on January 16, 2024.
We outline our vision of one, one team,
building cohesive teams to leverage
synergies and complimentary strength to
top to tap into new business
opportunities.
In this endeavors, we realigned our
teams to work collaboratively under a
unified product and business practice.
Today, I'm pleased to share many of our
initiatives such as one call center, one
digital and one agency have started
yielding results. Any change of a
significant magnitude requires
continuous reinforcement and we continue
to learn as we co-create an environment
conducive conducive to growth,
innovation and collaboration.
Let me now update on update you on
industry trends and developments that we
have witnessed in the past few months of
financial year 2025.
For the quarter ended September 2024 as
per the data released by MOSPI the GDP
growth slowed down to 5.4% as compared
to 8.1% in the corresponding quarter of
previous year. Let me dwell on certain
key data points during last quarter
which can have an impact on GI industry
at large.
On the corporate side, the industry
supporting infrastructure and
construction like steel, cement and
commercial vehicle sales witness muted
growth as government spending towards
capital expend capital expenditure
remains sluggish which we also which is
also reflecting in the commercial lines
of general insurance industry.
On the auto sector, the industry
reported muted growth in quarter 3 of
2025 as per CM with growth in private
car at 4 and a half% growth in two-heer
at 3% and degrowth in CV at.5%.
The retail numbers as reported by FA has
seen improvement in the growth on
account of uptick in rural demand with
private cars growing at 5.9%, two
wheeler at 12.4% and CV at 1.6%.
Health insurance continues to be the
fastest growing and largest contributor
of the industry in the GDPI mix
attracting significant investment across
stakeholders.
The bank credit growth also moderated to
11% due to slowdown in credit to NBSC
segment and unsecured loans. In
addition, the MSI sector growth also got
adversely impacted due to structural
changes.
Further as we move towards the next
quarter, we believe in based spending,
lower insurance penetration and hence
risk it governance in a conducive
regulatory environment is expected to
have a positive impact on general
insurance sector over medium to long
term. Coming to the regulatory update,
general insurers are mandated to
recognize premium for long-term products
on a one by basis effective October 1st,
2024.
As an industry, new motor policies due
to long-term TP were recognized on one
byN basis. There is thus there is no
impact on this line of business. The
premium under long-term health and other
line of business were re recognized in
the year of underwriting itself. This
change has an impact on the reporting of
health and other line of business for
the industry for quarter 3 of financial
year 2025. However, this does not impact
the economic value. So we continue to
evaluate business opportunities which is
expected to deliver sustained returns to
stakeholders.
Secondly on solveny norms the authority
issue guidelines on on inadmissibility
of asset which changes disallowance of
receivable primary from net basis to
gross basis. Due to this there's
reduction of 30 basis points in our
solveny ratio as at March 30 as a
December 31st 2024. Consequently, our
solveny ratio was 2.36 as a December
31st, 2024, which is higher than the
minimum regulatory requirement of 1.5.
Thus, this change does not impact our
growth journey. The general insurance
council has represented the matter to
the authority emphasizing the
significant implication of this change
on the solveny position for the industry
player.
Now coming to the industry growth, gross
direct premium income has grown by 9.5%
and 7.8% for quarter 3 of financial year
2025 and 9 month financial year 2025
respectively as published by GI council.
Excluding crop and male segment, the
industry registered a growth of 5.7%
and 9.1% for quarter 3 financial year
2025 and 9 month 2025 respectively.
Speaking on the specific segments within
the industry during the quarter under
motor insurance the industry view at
7.6% for quarter three financial year
2025 the total numbers of vehicles sold
as per CM data is approximately 3.1
million private car 15 million two
wheelers and 1.2 2 million CV for 9
months financial year 2025. The health
segment during the quarter delivered
doubledigit growth within the group
health within this group health view at
14.6% and retail health view at 6.6%
yearonear in quarter C financial year
2025. Further subdue trade disment by
financial institutions has resulted in a
slow slower growth of health business
health benefit business.
The commercial line segment debut at
8.4%. Within this, the fire continued to
degrow resisting a degrowth of 22% on
account of pricing pressure. We expect
the pricing to improve in the fire
segment in the coming months. Now
speaking of the underwriting performance
for the industry, the command combined
ratio for the industry was turned to
113.3%
from for H1 of 2025 as against triple
1.9%
for H1 of 2024 largely on account of
increase in expense ratio for the motor
business. The industry combined ratio
worsened to 124.8% in H1 financial year
2025 from 119.4% in H1 of 2024. I will
now speak about the company's
performance across key business segments
during quarter 3 financial year 2025.
The company's GDPI for quarter 3
financial year 2025 registered a growth
of 4.8%
with one by an accounting norm the
company registered degrowth of.3% as
again the industry growth of 9.5%.
During the same period excluding crop
and mass health the company degree by 7%
as compared to industry growth of 5.7%.
In commercial line segment we remain
cautious due to continued pricing
pressure resulting in degrowth of 8.6%.
However we continue to maintain a market
share in the segment. Further we have
maintained a leadership position in
liability and marine cargo segment. In
motor we give a 9.4% 4% for quarter 3
financial year 2025 as against the
industry growth of 7.6%.
Our growth in this segment was driven by
festive le sales as well as old book.
During this quarter we sustained a
balanced portfolio with a mix of private
car, two-wheer and TV at 52.9, 26.7 and
20.4 respectively.
Moving to the health business during the
quarter we grew at 10.3% for quarter 3
financial year at 2025 and with one by
accounting now we dee at 4.6%.
Within health a retail health segment
registered a growth at 44.3%.
With one by an accounting norm the
growth was at 19.1% as as against
industry growth of 6.6%.
during the same period. Resultantly, we
gained market share as retail health
reaching 3.2% in quarter 3 financial
year 2025.
As updated updated in our previous call,
we continue to invest in product
innovation and technology integration.
This includes upgrades to elevate
revamping our super topper productivate
booster and travel product trip secure
plus during the quarter. In the group
health employer employee segment, we
continue to maintain cautious approach
on account of competitive intensity
resulting in muted growth at 1.1% in
quarter 3 financial year 2025.
Our group other business grew at 1.8%
with 1 by accounting norm that the
growth in this segment was at 33% during
the same period.
We continue to harness our digital
capabilities to enhance customer
experience leading to a customerf facing
digital business growing at growth of
9.9% constituting 7.4% of our overall
GDPI.
During the quarter, our take care app
has surpassed 13.2 million user
downloads, registering a premium of 64.2
million for quarter 3 financial year
2025. Additionally, I would like to
highlight efforts being undertaken
towards improving claims efficiencies
across retail line of business. Our
prefer partner network serviced 73.6%
of our nonm claims in quarter 3
financial year 2025 as again 57.3 in
quarter 3 of financial year 2024.
Our average claim settlement period of
retail line of business has seen
improvement. It has improved from 6 days
in financial year 2024 to 5 days in 9
month financial year 2025 for motor and
from 5 days in financial year 2024 to 3
days in 9 month financial year 2025 for
health our initiative which was launched
in April of 2024 offer an onground
support to over 65,000 customers across
2,500 of Twitter network. We continue to
monitor our customer feedback from
independent agencies in the form of net
promoter score steady on regular basis.
Our NPS continues to be healthy at 69
and 65 for financial year 2025 for
health and motor claims respectively
supported by customer trust. In all the
previous update we discussed on the core
business and technology transformation
project arrive we initiated
transformation journey of our health
business and have now achieved a
critical milestone by rolling out a
flagship retail indemnity product
elevate on our new core platform. Going
forward we expect a shorter period of
development of products on our new
system.
We are excited to see this extending
across our product categories under the
health business and beyond. We firmly
believe project will be a key enabler of
our vision of one is one team. As we
conclude, we are positive and determined
to achieve profitable outcomes led by
multi-product multi-distribution
strategy focus on product innovation,
data analytics and digital enhancement
with our guiding force of one team. I
will now request Gopal to take through
the financial numbers for the recent
concluded quarter and 9 months. Thanks
Sanjie and good evening to each one of
you. I will now give you a brief
overview of the financial performance of
the recently concluded quarter and 9
months. We have uploaded the results
presentation on our website. You can
access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers
with effect from October 1, 2024.
Long-term products are accounted on a 1
byN basis as mandated by the regulator.
Hence quarter 3 and 9 months numbers of
this year are not comparable with prior
periods or prior years. Please also
refer to slide number 15 of our investor
presentation for further details uh on
this. The gross direct premium income of
the company was at rupees 2 206.23
billion in 9 months of this year as
against 187.03 billion in 9 months of
last year. A growth of 10.3%
as against industry growth of 7.8%. GDPI
was rupes 62.14 billion in quarter 3 as
against rupes 62.3 billion in quarter 3
last year. A deg growth of.3% as against
industry growth of 9.5%.
On the retail side of the business GDP
of motor was rupes 31.09 in quarter 3 as
against rupees 28.42 billion in quarter
3 last year registering a growth of
9.4%.
The advanced premium numbers for motor
segment was rupes 36.44 44 billion as at
December 31, 2024 as against 35.13
billion as at September 30, 2024. GDP of
the health segment was rupes 13.16
billion in quarter 325 as against rupes
13.79 billion in quarter 324 registering
a deg. Our agent which included the
point of sale distribution count was 1
lakh 40,77 at December 31 2024 up from 1
lak 33683
as at September 32 2024 GDP of the
commercial lines was rupes 14.63 in Q3
this year as against rupes 16 billion in
Q3 FI24 registering a deg growth of
8.6%. Resultantly the combined ratio was
102.9% in 9 months FI25
as against 103.7 in 9 months last year.
The combined ratio was 102.7 in quarter
3 of the current year as against 103.6%
in quarter 3 FI24 excluding the impact
of CAT losses of rupees 94 billion in 9
months FI25 and rupees 1.37 billion in 9
months FI24. The combined ratio was
102.3%
and 102.6% 6% respectively. Excluding
the impact of CAT losses of rupees.54
billion in Q3 FI24, the combined ratio
was 102.3%.
There were no major catastrophic losses
for Q3 FI25. Our investment assets
during the quarter rose to rupees 515.97
billion at December 31, 2024, up from
515.57 billion at September 30, 2024. or
investment leverage net of borrowing was
3.76 times as at December 31, 2024 as
against 3.91 times at September 30,
2024. Investment income was at rupees
33.73 billion in 9 months FI25 as
against rupees 26.57 billion in 9 months
FI24. On a quarterly basis, investment
income was rupees 11.21 billion in Q3
FI25 as against rupees 8.57 billion in
Q3 FI24. Our capital gains neck of
impairment investment assets stood at
rupees 7.96 billion in 9 month FI25 as
compared to rupees 3 uh 95 billion in 9
month FI24. Capital gains net of
impairment on investment investment
assets stood at rupees 2.76 billion in
Q3 FI25 as compared to rupees 1.08
billion in Q3 FI24.
Our profit before tax grew by 42.8% 8%
at rupees 26.53 billion in 9 months FI25
as against rupes 18.57 billion in 9
months FI24 whereas PBT grew by 67.3% at
rupees 9.6 6 billion in Q3 FI25 as
against rupees 5.74 billion in Q3 FI24.
Consequently, profit after tax grew by
42.9%
at rupees 19.99 billion in 9 months FI
this year as against rupees 13.99
billion in 9 months FI24. PAT grew by
67.9% at rupees 7.24 billion in Q3 FI25
up from rupees 4.31 billion in Q3 FI24.
Return on average equity was 20.8 8% in
9 months this year as against 17.1% in 9
months of the last year. The return on
equity for this quarter of the current
year was 21.5% as against 15.3% in Q3
FI24. Solveny ratio was at 2.36 times.
This is after factoring in the impact of
30 basis points as Sanji had mentioned
as at December 31, 2024 as against 2.65
65 times as at September 30, 2024 which
continued to be higher than the
regulatory minimum of 1.5 times. As I
conclude, I would like to state that we
are aligned with our ethos of driving
profitable growth, consistent and
sustainable value creation for all our
stakeholders while ensuring that the
interest of policy holders are in the
forefront at all times. I would like to
thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we'll be happy to take
questions that you have. Thank you.
Thank you very much. We will now begin
the question and answer session. Anyone
who wishes to ask a question may press
star and one on their touchstone
telephone. If you wish to remove
yourself from the question queue, you
may press star and two. Participants are
requested to use handsets while asking a
question.
Ladies and gentlemen, we will wait for a
moment while the question Q assembles.
We'll take our first question from the
line of Nishin Savate from Kotak
Institutional Equities. Please go ahead.
Uh hi uh thanks for uh taking my
question and uh you know congrats for a
good set of numbers. Uh you know just uh
a little bit of commentary on the motor
side. You know we can see the loss
ratios uh you know improving uh for you
uh both on a sequential and annual basis
and uh significant improvement very
specifically on the third party side. Uh
so just uh just just if you could give
some commentary in terms of you know
what's happening over here how the
competitive intensity and I believe we
have gained market share in this quarter
in both the segments.
Yeah. So Nishant I think u you're right
I think uh clearly uh over the last uh
few years if you'd have seen I think we
have been slightly selective in the way
we have been writing the risks and
therefore to that extent uh that has
kind of stood us in times of uh
reflection on the combined outcomes. Um
having said that I think obviously what
where what we are seeing right now is u
therefore u uh renewed opportunities in
the way we can write risks and that's
reflective also in terms of the increase
in the market share that we have seen
relative to 9 months of last year. uh
generally if you see I think we have
been able to see particularly let's say
in this particular quarter uh between
new and renewal I think largely the
growth has been more or less similar
when you look at at a category level and
therefore we continue to look for
opportunities in each of private car
two-heer CV and broadly if you look at
the mix it's in line with what we have
normally seen over uh prior periods uh
on the loss experience specifically this
change I think this is something that we
keep speaking about. Um obviously when
we kind of uh write or maybe risk select
the portfolio we have an ultimate loss
experience that we kind of uh go with an
assumption at the time of writing the
risk and over a period of time I think
you given the fact that we have
generally been prudent/conservative in
our loss estimates as the loss
experiences starts to develop I mean we
can see this not just for uh this year
across years we have been able to see
let's say favorable loss development and
that starts to getting that starts to
get reflected on the numbers um as we
kind of see across different financial
periods. uh so that's where we are but
broadly if you ask me I think in terms
of the overall loss ratio range that
I've kind of spoken about even in the
past and again as I keep saying uh it's
always better to look at motor as a
category rather than looking at own
damage and third party uh independently
and the range that we have spoken about
running overall motor uh in that range
of uh 65 to 67 I think that's broadly
the range that we believe uh we should
continue to see as an outcome in terms
of the portfolio experience. So that's
where we are. Um and uh and and the
positive news is I think some of the
market participants possibly who had
kind of gone quite aggressive uh in the
past uh you can clearly see most of
those companies when you look at their
individual uh month-on-month growth
numbers. Uh clearly there is a there has
been a element of calibration that has
happened and that's also reflective in
the outcomes that these companies had to
exhibit in some of their combined ratio
outcomes. So so that's where we are. We
continue to be uh cautious in building
the book and so far as the ethos on uh
writing or selecting the portfolios
continues to remain the same as in we
will keep looking for on a sustained
basis an economic output uh which we
think will be viable from a longerterm
perspective. No, no, absolutely. And
also just the thing is uh in our mindset
I think we will do what makes sense to
us. Market share of course this year
looks better but uh uh we also had
explained the market maybe almost four
quarters back in terms of why our market
share is where it is. So it's more of an
outcome uh of uh how multiple factors uh
work. It's not something that we chase,
you know,
it's more driven by outcome and as in
when it makes
uh us look good. It's primarily driven
by an ecosystem development uh as we
continue to pursue what we believe makes
sense for us.
Sure. and and the delta this quarter or
uh you know the the much lower you know
loss ratio in TP this quarter uh you
know could it be uh you know uh maybe
because of better releases this quarter
again as we keep saying mish I think uh
TP again I have spoken in numerous
occasions even in the past right I think
um given that it's obviously and all of
you understand uh you all have been
tracking us uh pretty much for a very
long period of time uh so and this is
clearly a book which is much more long
tail in terms of loss development ment
loss experiences obviously have to be
looked at over a period of time and as I
said obviously the level of prudence
that we kind of go with in terms of a
reserving estimate that stands pretty
much intact absolutely no change in the
philosophy of reserving and therefore as
the portfolio actually starts to
experience outcomes you could see let's
say some of the releases play out at
different periods it could be in a
particular quarter it could be in a
particular financial year but on an
overall small basis. Which is why if you
look at our reserving triangle now that
you also have a specific uh triangle
outcome in the context of third party as
well and there again you will see
consistently for us there are small
amount of favorable launch developments
that we have seen over years. This is
again not just for one quarter or one
year or uh two years. It's across
financial periods that we have been able
to see some small amount of uh favorable
development and that and hence to that
extent the the approach to reserving
will continue in terms of a favorable
loss development and that's how we have
been kind of going about uh risk
selection as I talked about and just
finally uh in this backdrop uh you know
do we uh really sort of uh now expect uh
uh tariff hike uh third party tariff
hike this year so there is again you
know uh well industry is expecting it
for last uh few years and uh it's not
something which we control uh the answer
to this is yes we do expect a hike but
uh can it or can can it come can it not
it's something which will uh come from
the regulator as well as mo the way they
decided so but we do believe yes it's
been 3 to four years and there might be
uh possibly the high which you'll get
for next financial year.
Sure. Thank you very much and all the
best. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen, in order to ensure
that the management is able to answer
queries from all participants, please
restrict your questions to two at a
time. You may join back the queue for
follow-up questions.
Next question is from the line of Pre
Jen from Motila Losal. Please go ahead.
Yeah. Hi. Uh congrats on a very good set
of numbers. uh just you know just
harping Gopal on this point on uh the
loss ratio on the uh motor side again uh
uh so you were mentioning that for the
motor as a piece we should be looking at
a loss ratio of 65 to 67%
uh but we are way below that currently
so would you still say that you know uh
the full year number would be in that
range or we should
uh that's more of a longerterm uh loss
ratio that you would be looking at. Uh
that's my first question. Uh second is
on the health loss ratio. Uh could you
give the give the granularity on you
know how much was the retail health loss
ratio and how much was the employer
employee uh loss ratio. Um and uh just
on this you know on the fire piece you
mentioned that uh there could be uh you
know price hike and uh uh so so why
would that be because your loss ratio
outcomes seems to be pretty uh
controlled at 50.1%.
Uh yeah that would be my questions.
Perfect. So maybe I'll go the reverse
sequence. Uh so let me start with the
commercial line. Um so again pre I think
all of you understand that uh commercial
lines in general is a relatively high
exposure portfolio. So therefore to that
extent uh you can obviously see
experiences which could be relatively
with low frequency high severity
outcomes and therefore in again in a
given period you can obviously see
experiences on loss numbers which could
be significantly adverse or maybe at the
same time the portfolio will logically
kind of in case if you don't have large
number of catastrophic events then what
you normally expect as additional losses
is what how the portfolio will develop.
Um I think clearly you have seen not
just in the Indian market I think across
the globe you have clearly seen
increased incidences of uh some of these
catastrophic events impacting insurers
reinsurers customers at large and
therefore clearly when you look at the
overall portfolio outcome from a market
standpoint I think it's leading to an
outcome where the experiences from a
let's say from a reinsurance standpoint
may not be necessarily in that sense
viable at the level of pricing that they
have given to the market at large. So
hence given the fact that some of these
events are more frequent more in numbers
there is obviously a need for the entire
market across stakeholders to look at
what should be the level of price that
you should kind of offer for risk
selection. Uh equally in the past for
example you would have seen periods of
very long periods of soft pricing as
well. So that's how the nature of the uh
business is. You will obviously see
through various price cycles at at
sometimes you will obviously as I said
experience soft pricing currently it's a
regime where maybe because of these
increased incidences you will see some
bit of hardening in price and hence at
least which is where we we are kind of
coming from um the expectation is at
least so far as the uh quarter 4 and and
more importantly the April one renewals
which will largely be the where bulk of
the corporate renewals will
we do expect the overall market to be
far more uh sensible in so far as
pricing those risks are concerned. So
that's where we are and that's that
that's what we believe from an overall
positive sentiment. Uh to your point on
the health loss breakdown as what uh
every quarter we keep asking for this uh
split uh I think on the corporate health
which is a GHI segment again I will give
the quarter three numbers for the both
the segments first which is corporate
health and then retail indemnity. So for
corporate health quarter 3 of last year
that number was 93.1
that number for this quarter 3 is at
97.2
and retail indemnity numbers last year
was 66% which is down to about 65%.
On a 9 month basis again in the same
sequence corporate health last year was
95.8
which is currently about 97.7
and the retail indemnity numbers which
was 65.6 six for 9 months last year that
number stands at about 69.1%.
uh but more than let's say some of these
numbers in general I think what we have
seen is uh uh I think pretty much we do
see uh maybe some continuation of uh
increased incidences of claims playing
out uh in the context of uh uh some of
the in the health segment specifically
and therefore in line with what we had
spoken even in quarter one we said we
will obviously observe for the
development of this increased incences
over the next few quarters uh so That's
where we are and in that context is
where the numbers are for the health
loss numbers. To your last point on u
motor I think the range that we kind of
spoke about at 65 to 67 you're
absolutely right. I think that's
obviously the preferred range at which
we would want to kind of run the book
again not just over a one or two year
horizon. That's something that we would
want to kind of look at it over a much
more longerterm play. Having said that,
I think obviously in now when it comes
to specific financial periods, it could
be purely a function of what kind of mix
of business that you write. U and again
we have discussed this in the past you
particularly when it comes to new motor
that typically comes with a relatively
low loss outcome but possibly a slightly
higher cost of acquisition. But equally
on the flip side when you kind of start
to source more of the renewal or let's
say the older book that invariably comes
with a slightly higher loss outcomes but
obviously a lower cost of acquisition.
So that's how we manage the overall
portfolio in the way how we see the
market opportunity but over a medium to
long-term I think the range that we are
comfortable with to operate with will be
between that 65 to 67% for motor as a
category.
You got that any price contemplating in
the health segment?
I think that's something that we keep
looking for pre and uh and we have and
we have not shied away from taking a
price change. Uh you would recollect
again slightly going back to some of our
conversations even in the past. U if you
have to go back maybe almost four years
back quarter 3 2021 um at that point of
time we did affect an average price
increase of roughly about 8% of the
overall renewal book. uh and then
roughly about one and a half two years
thereafter again uh we had kind of
affected a price increase which ranged
anywhere between uh 20 to 22%. So in
general I think again on the retail
indemnity book specifically again we
have spoken about the fact that the
range that we are comfortable on running
the book is a loss ratio of around that
range between 65 to 70% more towards I
would say slightly on the high higher
end of the range u and at this point of
time I think as you would have seen the
outcome largely is kind of playing out
within the range that we are comfortable
with but having said that I think if the
portfolio warrants any kind of a price
division we will not shy away from
taking one.
got there. Thank you. Thank you. Thank
you. Participants are requested to
restrict to two questions. Please, we
have a next question from the line of
Sankit Koda from Aendas Park. Please go
ahead. Yeah. Uh thank you for the
opportunity. Uh so Gopal, you said that
you want to work motor TP on motor loss
ratio in the range of 60 to 65. If I
take at the other end for motor TP at
65, is it fair to assume that in Q4 um
the loss ratios in motor TP will be more
70 to 75 compared to what you have
reported 60.1 uh for 9 months FI25. So
that's that's a fair assumption to make
to to remain conservative with respect
to motor TP reserving. Yeah. Again I I
mean just for the sake of uh reiterating
I will keep saying that uh um I would
always urge all of you to look at
numbers more over longerterm horizon
particularly for motor third party. Uh
it would be completely in that sense
when I when I use this to say that uh
ideally quarters will have multiple
factors to it. Um as I just mentioned
one factor would be in terms of uh the
kind of business mix that we see as an
opportunity. So that by itself will
determine what the loss ratio outcome
could be. And as I said, we keep looking
for the outcome of the loss development
of the book that we have written in the
past. And this is not just something
that we do at a particular point. This
is something that we keep evaluating
every quarter. Um and that would be true
even for quarter 4. um and in case if
any of the past book reflects something
better in terms of outcome then
obviously to that extent you will see
some of the uh impact play out even in
quarter 4 as well uh so hence uh I think
rather than talking about a point
estimate or a point number for a
particular period it's better that we
keep looking at which is where I said
the medium to long-term range on motor
as a category uh because again I think
this is something that all of you
understand it's always in that sense
Since Given the fact that motor own
damage is free to price, motor third
party is fixed in tariff, better to look
at motor as a category rather than
trying to even split between motor own
damage and third party. And hence just
to kind of reiterate medium to long-term
range that we're comfortable on running
the book will be between 65 to 67%.
Got it. Uh and and uh and see see you
reported uh 102 on 1 byn uh and and
102.8 on if you exclude uh 1 by n. So,
so the management guidance was to end up
with 102 for FI25 and probably 101.5 for
the fourth quarter. So, so even
factoring a bit of negative impact from
one byn do you still continue to
maintain that guidance to play out for
the full year and and and if I take exit
as 101.5 for the fourth quarter should
we fairly assume that is the number
which will be there to 4526 and and last
and and the second thing is that if you
can break down the exact growth of motor
into new and old vehicle the way you did
it last time. Yeah. So maybe I think I
will give you the numbers for uh new and
old. This is again I'm just kind of
giving you for quarter three. Uh so new
was uh again 9.5 which is what I just
mentioned in response to one of the
calls. Largely the numbers were similar
and 9.5% growth for new and almost a
similar number of 9.3% for the old. So
as a category the overall growth was
9.4%.
Okay. And on the guidance part that you
spoke about uh clearly as we had put
across as to where we want to finish the
whole year. Uh at that point of time uh
there was no visibility that one by will
come and when such uh changes happen the
configuration of product which we
procure from the market also can go
through a transformation. Uh there's no
reason to believe that directionally we
are not there but at the same time we
also have to evaluate what the
opportunity comes through. So it's a
combination of all these aspects that
will uh decide the way forward. Uh it's
early days is the first quarter where
the industry and us are giving numbers
which are on a one by basis. Uh and the
strange part is the configuration where
the first six months are not on one by
and this quarter is one by hand. So to
that extent it will uh it will play out
over the course uh of time and the
industry's uh performance which we spoke
about when I said has moved to 113 uh
whereas it was 111 so it's kind of
relatively got worsened off so all of
these factors will also but what we also
stay committed is besides we combine the
ROE range that we want to operate which
we spoke about it uh when we have met up
so it's a combin is something which is
keeping us excited in terms of doing
collection also.
Okay, perfect. That's it from my side.
Thank you. Okay, thanks. Thank you.
Thank you. Next question is from the
line of Nidish Jen from Invest. Please
go ahead.
Uh thanks for the opportunity. The first
question is on this 1 byN. Uh has the
impact has been passed on to the
distributor and uh so are they also
getting commission on a yearly basis and
uh do you expect any impact on the
business growth because of that?
Uh the answer is yes. Uh it's regulatory
and whatever needs to be done is so it
will be also taken where the annuity
commission payment will happen to the
distributor. uh as far as growth is
concerned uh there is an overarching
impact in terms of long-term product
being sold but internally from an our
organization perspective the economic
value that comes in selling uh the
long-term product stays intact so we
continue to pursue uh in the market uh
selling long-term products the
accounting part of it will emanate as
and when it happens and yeah so I think
I think the only thing that I will just
add to what Sanjiv rightly said I I
think uh uh this is the first quarter uh
and and therefore to that extent the
market practices will also see an
evolution um in terms of some of these
changes uh uh that gets played out. So
for example when uh 6 years back when
the regulator had mandated let's say
third party mandatory for 3 years 5
years uh in between there were changes
uh in terms of the product construct to
get motor uh line of business recognized
on a one by prescription similar to what
you see for the rest of the lines as we
speak today. Uh so those practices
obviously kind of evolve over a period
of time and hence we will obviously
watch the market developments very very
closely. Um obviously I think the the
intent when you look at it from a
regulatory standpoint I think is very
very positive uh in the way they have
kind of uh wanted this particular change
and therefore our practices will be very
clear to make sure that uh we clearly
kind of meet regulatory expectations but
obviously we will keep a very close
watch on market developments as well and
keep kind of taking actions
corresponding to that. Yeah. And also if
I was a distributor and if I'm able to
do a long-term health, there is no
reason because it is one and that should
go through a change. Uh what you're not
getting in one year on the front end
business you will get over three years.
So there's an annual income uh that will
flow over a period of time. So there is
there can be a short-term thought
process. If you're not getting it, you
may not want to pursue with it.
Hopefully better sales will prevail and
they will also look at economic value
and go ahead and stay long-term uh as
always required.
Uh sure. Uh uh second question is on the
reinsurance. Uh the retention ratio has
increased quite materially this quarter
uh to 82%. Uh so is there any change in
strategy with respect to reinsurance?
So honestly there is a business. So if
you ask us uh our insurance programs
typically get decided at the beginning
of the year I think that's what we have
mentioned earlier as well. uh and um
again purely it's it's a function of uh
what is a split between mix of corporate
mix of retail and within that uh if you
recolct in the past we have spoken about
let's say in the context of health for
example on health indemnity as a line of
business we have always operated without
in that sense leave aside the obligatory
which is true for everyone in the market
but other than the obligatory
reinsurance we don't have any other
reinsurance requirements from a health
indemnity standpoint
on health benefit as a category not just
again this year across years we have
obviously kind of operated on a
reinsurance structure and hence and if
you recollect particularly not just
again this quarter this year in general
I think the health benefit segment has
seen an impact on growth and therefore
to that extent that will obviously have
an impact on the net retention numbers
so that's one second for whatever it is
even quarter three does have an element
of uh corporate business as well. It's
not that corporate business comes down
to zero and there the approach for us
again if you look at it over a 9month
basis we have been very very selective
largely we have tried to kind of hold on
to maintaining market share in that
particular category and uh given the
fact that that particular business is
slightly in that in that sense subdued
that again kind of contributes to the
overall uh retention numbers but if you
see the overall retention number the way
we kind of look at it I mean on the net
premium to gross premium I think at
least if you look at it on a 9mon basis
at least the number stands at roughly
I'm talking about the current year uh if
you look at it on a uh even with the 1
by n uh impact uh I think the retention
numbers will be roughly at about 72%. I
think that's where we are. And to answer
your point, no change in the reinsurance
strategy, nothing specific. It's not a
case where we had an element of
reinsurance for the first 6 months or
something and suddenly we have decided
to kind of change our approach to
reinsurance. Nothing of no significant
change therein. And the other aspect is
the bulk of the reinsurance renewal
conversations will now happen in quarter
4 for the next financial year.
Okay. And last question is on claims
initiatives that you're taking. I'm
sorry to interrupt Nesh. Can you please
join back the queue? Okay, sure. Thank
you. Sure. Sure. Thanks. We have our
next question from the line of Jan
Karote from Jeff. Please go ahead. Uh,
thank you for the opportunity. First
questions mode please. Not very clear.
Uh, thank you for the opportunity. Uh,
first question is on the competitive
scenario. Uh, given that we are
approaching the EOM glide path uh, last
couple of uh, quarters. uh how do you
see it play out over the next year and
specifically the impact on that is
having on group health and fire uh and
how what would be our sort of uh stance
in in in case it intensifies uh going
into the next say four to six quarters
uh that's the first question I I'll come
back with the second one so J uh clearly
our stand has been pretty clear on that
uh we continue to operate within the
guidelines and there is no reason under
any circumstances we would like to
violate that. Uh as in when we see
intensity building up uh we would choose
to withdraw rather than participate in
uh that kind of a you know uh business
intensity. The another point is that the
regulator has taken certain actions. So
uh in terms of expecting companies which
are not within the guidelines to fall in
line uh with that there is possibility
that it will get disciplined and we will
not see a rush in pricing. If you see
business lines like GHI and some others
uh further going low we would exchange
rather than participate. So we have
absolute clarity as a team uh to let go
what is not making commercial sense for
us.
Uh so do you see this uh playing out in
the claims of your competition and and
by when do you expect some more
rationality on the pricing in these
products uh in any any timeline? We are
we are no one to judge in terms of what
everyone else will do. But that being
said uh we did speak about where fire
went and where fire is expected to be.
So anything which goes below a threshold
uh will tend to autocorrect itself uh as
it's not uh viable
it's it will play out look it will play
out it's not that it will not play out
but there's a point of time when others
will and we respect that we like to fall
in line for EOM if and manage this
subsequently as and when things grow up
but my sheer presumption is that each
one of us who operates in the industry
wants to run the business in a
profitable manner and better sense will
prevail uh over a period of time.
Okay. The second question is on IFRS. Uh
we know we haven't uh you know we've
guided or at least indicated on some
improvement on the combined ratio. Uh
but it's been uh you know almost three
four quarters now. Uh any any more uh
disclosures or any anything that you
have gone back and and can help us uh
understand what could be the possible
impact. So uh on IFRS obviously as when
the rules come in we will fall in line.
Uh there is there is no question of the
not falling in line. They've also spoken
about the overall benefit it can have on
account of discounting of reserving and
also deferred you know expenses coming
into play. It will emanate in time to
come. But one fundamental thing which we
all have to understand is that this is
just mode of accounting right. The
economic value that gets given whether
it's one by whether it's FRS all of it
is part of the process in which manner
you will do the accounting of it the
business being sought the long-term
value that is to get created they all
remain similar you can project this
numbers in multiple manner it doesn't
change how we want to operate it's not
that IFRS will change the manner in
which you want to do business they still
will like to do what we are pursuing at
this point of time so there is
excitement of uh that coming through and
we will be more than happy. In fact, we
are very clear to say that why only
large fair everybody in the industry
should start publishing on FRS as this
is any indicative timeline by when will
you to join back the queue please as we
have other participants waiting. Thank
you. Thank you.
Next question is from the line of
Subramanyan Ayel from Morgan Stanley.
Please go ahead.
Uh hi uh thanks for the opportunity. Uh
I had an accounting question. So on
slide number 15 you have given basically
the comparison between uh profits
excluding 1 by and without inv
um and u you have given the GDPI and
PAT. So uh PAT is actually higher under
the with 1 by impact. So is it fair to
conclude that your uh commissions are
lower because of deferrals uh under with
1 by method and that's what is resulting
in the higher profits.
Subu again uh u this is again uh which
is why I kind of responded to say that
uh the prescription under one by need
not necessarily be uh in terms of
outcome uh go in the direction of only
an increase in profits. uh because again
this will be a function of uh what kind
of business mix that you source uh what
is the kind of uh reinsurance structures
that you may have in practice uh and
what is the kind of acquisition cost
that you kind of relate to uh with
respect to sourcing any of those
businesses. So there are multiple
factors which will drive let's say an
outcome when you look at it from a
transition to a one by flash without a 1
by uh uh outcomes. Now talking specific
in the context of quarter three I think
obviously this has been a quarter where
we were just kind of talking about in
general I think the credit link
dispersement uh across financial
institutions have clearly been muted and
obviously to that extent and we have
been one of the key writers of some of
those risks and that's an area where I
said we have always been historically
operating also with a reinsurance
structure so the fact that the business
growth has been relatively subdued
obviously that does have an impact both
in terms of growth in premiums and
therefore correspondingly the impact
that it has I mean when you look at it 1
by n effectively the prescription is to
say that whatever acquisition cost that
you incur you defer it over the contract
period similarly if there is an element
of reinsurance income that you may have
that is something again you defer it
over the policy contract so in a quarter
if you do see businesses where you
already had an element of a reinsurance
arrangement and if that business gets
subdued then Therefore, the relative
impact in outcome will not necessarily
be the same as compared to a line of
business. For example, in quarter 3, we
also have contracts of other lines of
businesses where we don't have a
reinsurance arrangement, but there's a
cost of acquisition. And by this very
inherent nature of a transition to 1
byN, the cost gets deferred. There is
nothing in terms of income for us to
kind of defer over the policy period.
Leave aside the obligatory that's a very
very small component. So that's the
reason why you see an outcome for
quarter three in terms of profits to be
higher than what you would have normally
reported on a without one by an
approach. Now this can change going
ahead if let's say the proportion of mix
of businesses undergo a change in terms
of the various factors that I spoke the
outcome could be either reversed you
could possibly see a situation of
neutrality in terms of no change in
profits or equally you could see maybe
an outcome similar to what you are
seeing for quarter 3 this year. So lot
of moving parts. Uh so hence to that
extent very difficult to say attribute
uh any specific reasons but quarter
three this is the reason it has been
more more businesses which are long-term
hard the ones where there are only cost
of acquisitions to be amotized but
relatively there are no reinsurance
commissions to be
thanks that's very clear um wish you all
the best. Thank you. Thanks. Thank you.
Next question is from the line of
Madukar Lada from Noama Wealth
Management. Please go ahead.
Uh hi uh congratulations on a a very
good set of numbers. Uh couple of
questions from me. First see I see a
very sharp increase in commission uh
cost. Now uh can you explain uh what has
led to that and second is um in the new
1 byN uh now you know that that's the
way we will be reporting numbers. So
what should our uh guidance be in terms
of you know uh exit in Q4 for combined
ratio and also then uh what are we
looking at uh for the next uh few years.
So yeah it you know some help on that
would be uh very very uh useful. Yeah.
So Madukar again um I mean I will always
keep again kind of urging all of you to
look at uh numbers more on a combined
ratio prescription rather than even
looking at uh breakdown of that combined
into loss ratio and let's say maybe the
expense ratio and within that you are
maybe asking a question which is more
further breakdown on uh commission
numbers corresponding to that. Um so so
that so given the nature of the business
that we have you will obviously see a
mix of outcome as I just mentioned Q3 in
specific uh I think you have seen on bit
say for whatever corporate business that
we used to write in the past that
particular part of the business has been
muted and therefore to that extent you
will obviously see a relatively lower
cost of uh acquisition uh which
otherwise would have been there uh had
that particular growth of commercial
business been there in quarter three and
hence a large part of quarter three are
businesses which are fundamentally
driven in so far as the retail line of
opportunity is concerned and two quarter
three in general if you see it's a
period of festive season. uh so when you
kind of put both of this together you
will obviously find an outcome in terms
of even in the context of just the
commission numbers or let's say the
commission ratio you will obviously
possibly see an increase therein but at
the end of the day even as what Sanjay
mentioned I think for us I think what
what what is something that we are very
very conscious of is to make sure that
we run the overall operations at an
expense of management which cannot kind
of exceed 30%. So that's a that's a
guard guard rail for us is something
that we are very very conscious of and
two and more importantly I think for us
we will obviously keep looking for
outcomes in the form of combined ratios
on businesses and at the end of the day
we are all here to give as what we have
put also in the opening remarks which is
a sustained uh return on uh capital for
stakeholders. Uh so that's equally
important from an ROE outcome is
something that again we are very very
conscious of. uh I think the range that
we have spoken about is to be within
that range of 16 to 18% and as things it
starts to improve relative to the market
obviously we would want to see that
getting better as well. So those are
those are guardrails within which we
kind of operate with u and and to that
extent I would again urge each of you to
look at outcomes with some of these uh
uh guardrails as a benchmark and to your
point on what would be the outcome on
quarter four combined and maybe let's
say as we head into the next financial
year I think Sanjiv already kind of
responded to that in response to one of
the earlier questions I think again as
we keep saying let's say when we look at
quarter core two factors one we
obviously have to wait and see how the
environment in place because that action
that's a variable. Second, I think we
will have to see how the market
responds. I think what we have said our
our combined will again be uh in
relation to the industry outcomes at
least the first half seeks to indicate
that the market is slightly more adverse
uh compared to 111. It's at about 113.
So we'll wait and see how quarter 3
numbers are for the other players in the
market. And corresponding to that is how
our own quarter 4 outcomes will play
out. But what we are conscious of I
think in all fairness when we look at
maybe just the return on uh equity to
stakeholders I think the broad comfort
that we can give you is we should
definitely end the year within that
range of about 16 to 18%. And as we head
into the next year the approach to
writing risk will still remain the same
and then we will keep looking for
profitable opportunities. So you know
I'll give you a small perspective so
probably you'll get a better
understanding of what gopal also is
talking about it. If you look at a last
year number even before that commercial
business for us was uh clearly you know
uh doing a very good uh growth numbers
and you know that commercial business
overarchingly works in a combined ratio
which is far lower. So when we got when
we started working on the planning for
this year itself we had a belief that
commercial line per se remain secular on
the contribution which is what gopal
also you know alluded in this
conversation as things stand it's not
commercial line which has uh grown but
the retail line of business which is you
know we're talking about retail Indian
we're talking about motor line of
business which has given us growth and
when the configuration changes it's
pertinent to understand that the
combined ratio will also change but the
overall value that we want to give the
stakeholder may not get impacted at all.
So the so the obsession with command r
is I do understand from your angle but
how we look at businesses has to be
understood in a far more comprehensive
manner to give a particular level of
targeted roe there will be changes if
you had stuck to the same plan maybe
would we would have done what is
required on retail and still stuck to a
low growing growth so we would have done
a much lesser
uh top line as well as shown a better
combine but it would not have served the
purpose so the point that Gopal keeps
making is look at the business in a far
more comprehensive manner. We will have
to stay agile in terms of what
opportunities gets provided. We do not
want to while we do give guidance and we
did speak about it. We don't want to get
ourselves tied down because we have had
X combined number. We let go an
opportunity which will serve us much
better in long term. It's an overarching
thought which I want to put across and
why we'll have to also real time change
our plans as the market uh uh you know
forces us to react to it.
Understood sir. Got it. I'll I'll uh you
know come back in the queue. The queue.
Yeah. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you
mad. Next question is from the line of
Rishi Junjunwala from Institutional
Equities. Please go ahead. Yeah. Thank
you for the opportunity. I'm sorry to
interrupt Rishi. I request you to
restrict to one question please. Thank
you. Okay. I'll make it a long one.
Thank you. Uh well said. Yes. So uh so
just you know firstly um you know on the
investment leverage right? So if you
look at it, it's already down to 3.777
for us and uh there has been a sharp uh
decline in the last 6 months and this is
despite the fact that you know I'm
assuming that motor vehicle act related
benefits haven't really completely
played out as yet. So just wanted to
understand your thoughts in terms of uh
you know with or without uh that
implementation on a pan India basis
where do you see uh the investment uh
leverage uh uh you know stable out or
stabilize and a and a related question
to that is um you know 2 three years ago
we had given up this uh 20% roe and 100%
combined ratio uh target in order to
ensure that we are not missing out on
growth opportunities given that we are
now at 20% roe and uh uh combined ratios
are uh you know trending uh closer to
100. I mean we are still 200 whips away.
Um do you think there could be a
recalibration to that target um you know
in the medium term?
So uh so Rishi let me take again the
reverse sequence. Uh uh so I think if
you ask us uh the the the uh narrative
in terms of our intent to keep looking
for profitable growth opportunities
remains the same. So therefore to that
extent um do we stand committed to
staying within that return on equity
objective? Of course I think that pretty
much kind of stays intact. um and that's
a range why I kind of talked about uh in
the medium term given the level of
combined we should be kind of getting to
an outcome which could be between 16 to
18%. The reason why I'm saying this is
because uh you will still appreciate the
fact that we don't want to lose
opportunities for investment in areas
which will propel growth for uh in the
future. Uh so that's something that we
are very very conscious of and therefore
these investments which we have been
kind of speaking through even in the
past will entail an upfronting of
expense in the P&Ls and that by itself
when you look at it from an just from an
year's outcome it will possibly look at
maybe an ROE which may not be equal
exactly to 20%. for that matter of fact
but but these are investments which we
think is something that we should make
at this point of time the uh the effect
of which will play through maybe over
the next two three years. Uh but if you
ask us again the point that we keep
saying I think uh the economic objective
in terms of what we want to write
clearly is within that uh range of ro
objective that I responded in uh
response to one of the earlier
questions. Same thought process on
combined. I think uh the lens with which
we look at each of the business
opportunity again not just any
particular line across lines I think the
lens that we kind of apply is obviously
combined and equally ultimately the uh
returns that would kind of fetch to
stakeholders or the capital that is
being infused. So obviously that both of
this doesn't have not fundamentally
changed and we kind of stand committed
to the range that we have kind of spoken
through. uh but all of this have to be
looked at in the context of how the
market operates. Um and hence to that
extent uh this may be something that you
will see playing out over long term
assuming the market start responding
sensibly but uh but at times in case the
market uh responds more aggressively uh
uh in terms of competition then to that
extent maybe some of these petrices will
possibly get postponed by a year or two.
So that's where we are. Um on the first
point the investment leverage I think
again u this is again if you look at the
way the leverage gets computed obviously
there is a numerator which is the
investment assets and the denominator
which is let's say net worth u and then
investment assets is obviously in the
context of uh the various investments
some of these investments are carried at
a market value and these are point
estimates at a point of time and as you
would have seen particularly since
you're looking at the numbers on a
quarter three basis for example uh we
have seen obviously particularly equity
markets relatively exhibiting a slightly
more subdued sentiment and in that
context I think if you look at maybe the
markettomarket position that you would
have had of the book as at September
relative to as of December obviously at
a point of time that number would have
seen us uh seen us seen a decline uh so
that would have some some impact when
you look at the investment leverage
second I think uh again as what we have
been speaking there has also been a
relative slowdown in growth uh in
general for
And that by itself clearly also
contributes to the overall uh available
cash flows and that has also had an
impact in the overall uh investment
leverage. And third I think again
clearly when you look at particularly
for some of the commercial lines which
generally is very very profitable that's
also been a segment where we have not
seen as much of growth as what one would
have expected. So all these factors is
where we are on the leverage but as the
environment improves we should start
seeing the leverage kind of coming back.
uh and also just small thing uh thanks
Gopal is that uh that motor vehicle act
that you refer to Rishield is a faster
intimation then there'll be a lower
investment leverage not higher so uh uh
that's one small thing it's more driven
by cash flow and configuration in terms
of the nature of business that comes
through ironically as much I don't want
to uh but if you have a growth of pack
also that budget the denominator network
will go up and that itself will lead to
investment level going down I mean it's
more mathematical in that sense what I'm
But there are multiple things will go
in. Uh it's again an outcome. We do
understand the value of leverage in your
mind. Uh but we write business in terms
of what makes sense and this comes out
as an outcome. We do it's not that we
don't look at cash flow but that is not
the reason why we end up writing certain
businesses or eliminate any businesses.
Okay. Thank you so much. Thank you.
Thank you. We request participant to
restrict to one question please. We'll
take the next question from the line of
Avin Singh from MK Global. Please go
ahead.
Yeah. Hi. Uh thanks for the opportunity.
Great set of numbers. Just one question
again coming to that. I mean I recall
your kind of focus on combine not claims
and expenses but more on the expenses if
you put together. I mean so uh one that
uh is the regulator now kind of looking
for any kind of a change with their um
targets because the rule of game has
been changed in between uh with this one
by an accounting and if you can help us
I mean even on a kind of a commission
plus opex basis which are the business
lines particularly that is seeing a bit
of I would say intensified payouts or
competition on in terms of payout that
is leading to this overall opex
including commission Please thank yeah
so so again uh on the on the uh on the
point on uh EOM Avin uh uh so uh so the
firstly like we at this point of time I
think obviously I don't think the
regulator is contemplating anything
specific in terms of uh any change in
the thought process I think uh as a
regulator I think what they're looking
for is uh to make sure that the overall
industry operates within a defined
thresholds uh and at this point of time
that number stands at about 30% or 35%
as the case may be uh and there is uh
and this has been just put into practice
maybe since the last one year or so. So
hence to that extent to expect anything
suddenly changing
given even the given the change that
they have put in the context of 1 by or
thereabout at least that's something
that's not within our knowledge in terms
of whether the regulator is looking for
any specific changes to be made. So at
this point of time the limit of 30 or 35
uh stands intact. Having said that I
think what we at least understand uh
from the market is uh the regulator is
obviously keeping a very very close
watch on making sure that the larger
market players continue to make need to
make sure that they run their overall
operations at an AOM which is less than
uh 30 or 35 as the case may be. And if
you look at basis public uh disclosure
of uh financial outcomes still there are
a large number of players who even on an
FI24 basis have exceeded the threshold
and clearly from market we understand
that the regulator has asked each of
these companies to come out with a plan
of action to make sure that they are
able to kind of come down come within
the threshold. So that is where we are.
uh we don't think there's going to be
anything immediate in so far as change
in the expectations on meeting the
limits on expensive management is
concerned from a market perspective
to your second point on uh what are the
business lines that invariably kind of
contributes to let's say a high expense
of management again multiple factors uh
so for example the point that I made
saying that if you make any uh
investments and opportunities for the
future now that entails a cost that will
be a part of my expense of management
numbers today. So that will put that
will increase the uh ratio. Second, in
terms of the mix of business that you
write, which is what I explained
earlier, if I'm writing let's say an old
an it relatively new portfolio on the
motor side, that invariably comes with
maybe a low loss ratio, high expense. So
that will let's say uh result in a
higher expense numbers and the third
will be again given the fact that we are
driving a lot more on retail health. Uh
so that invariably comes with a slightly
higher cost of acquisition. So multiple
moving parts and that's the reason why I
keep saying look at more on combined as
compared to just the expense ratio
numbers.
Okay. Clear. Thank you. Thank you. Thank
you ladies and gentlemen. That was the
last question for today. I now hand the
call over to Mr. Sanju Mani for closing
comments. Over to you sir. Great. I
think uh thank you so much for joining
us. It's always a pleasure and your
questions also give us tremendous
clarity. Uh we look forward to
interacting with uh each one of you over
the course of next few weeks. Uh look
forward to your support as always and
have a great year ahead. Thank you so
much. Bye-bye. Thank you. Thank you. On
behalf of ICA Lombard General Insurance
Company, that concludes this conference.
Thank you for joining us and you may not
disconnect your lines.